Actually,
many people ask me about comedy, I will first
tell you that I have seen that there is
no respect for comedy, I have seen it
because comedy is the only art in the world in
which anyone can find fault, whether he knows it himself or
not, someone would say what a
bad thing, anyone can do it,
what uncle, my uncle can do it, this must be
funny uncle, then
[Music]
friend, people from any other art form do not have the courage to find
fault unless they themselves know it,
like singing, what
respect is there in singing, friend, if I tell you here,
you will say
wow Pandit Abhishek, what a
thing, and I sing very badly, people would
call me to birthday parties, don't you
sing Happy Birthday, ah,
actually I sang, he
threw the cake, I am not making it,
ah sorry brother, sorry friend,
everyone was singing, it came out of their mouth, on
top of that I cannot even learn singing, the
first one is like Suri,
you understand, now I cannot be T.T. Saare Gama,
why are the children sitting in the class teaching us T.
[Music]
you  I thought let's do one thing, let's
learn it privately, so a singing teacher
came to my house on the first day he was telling me
Abhishek, today is the first day, let's see what your level is,
sing and show me, I said ok sir, he
said a lot, sir I just took a breath, I took a very
dirty breath,
don't
take it again, sing after me, I said ok
sir, I said sir
what, I said no, listen to the tune, you
listen, sir is saying hold the note, Abhishek,
I said sir is saying
hold the note, I
hold it, friend, I said I don't know how to do it, do it, I said I am
not able to do it, sir, I said do it once, I will do it once, the
ability to hold the note is called
singing, that's
what kind of coaching is this
brother, then I will coach the athletic team of Olympics,
sister [ __ ], run faster, oh
run faster,
friend, you have to run faster than others, is it not that
difficult, actually I
like comedy, many
people respect such comedy, many
people keep asking me, actually you are a comedy
Why are you doing this? You should have done a job, it
is respected a lot. Yes, let me tell you
why I am doing this. I used to do comedy.
First, understand me.
I am a chemical engineer and
not just any chemical engineer who got a 40 and
passed, he got a 51.
Thank you, thank you, sit down, sit down. I was in my
final year at Punjab University, Chandigarh. When we reached the final year,
all my friends were getting jobs.
When the first friend among us got a
job, we were all sitting at his placement party. We were
very happy that, come on, friend,
jobs have started coming our way. We were all drinking.
My best friend
Chuchu and I also drank alcohol and were very happy that, come on,
friend, jobs have started coming our way
soon. We are fed up with student life. We have to
ask for money from our family for everything.
Once I get a job, I will directly block my family.
I kept getting jobs after jobs.
Everyone's Chuchu also got a job, that too
in Delhi where I wanted to. In the entire class,
only two kids got jobs, one mine
and one more.  There was a kid who didn't come to college after his second year,
okay, I'll count him, he
also didn't get a job, so I did what
Sonam Kapoor would have done in my place,
I talked to Papa, "Dad,
[Sangeet]
listen, does
anyone know you,
I said, companies aren't coming for
placements, right?" She said, "
How come you didn't get a job for four years? You haven't
done anything,
just movies here and there, that foolish cult,
where will you get a job for four years? If you did
n't study, you could have told me, my friend,
our money would have been wasted, we could have sent you to the village, we could have done
some farming." I
said, "Now you want me to get you a
job through a recommendation?" I said, "Yes, no,
this is not my job, I had to provide
education, I did the rest,
you look after yourself." I said, "
Please, Papa, how are you doing like this?
How are you treating your father? Uncle's job got a job,
everyone's got a job. Please, Papa, do me the
last favor, do me the last favor of my life. I wo
n't even talk to him.
I see,
I feel ashamed of you,
but I am proud of you."  Let's get it,
now my friends got jobs in Delhi,
Mumbai, Bangalore, Pune, my real father got me a
job in Bathinda,
Bathinda, Bathinda, you know, Uttara Punjab,
see, yes, I am there, I am seen taking drugs in the background,
and actually, Bathinda was not there, I wish it was Bathinda, there is a forest one and
a half hour inside Bathinda, it is
not a village, it is a forest, its name is
Talwandi
Saboo, Talwandi
Saboo, Bathinda is aspirational for the people there,
my mother's husband got me a job there,
and where did he get me a job, inside an oil
refinery, that means, he might accidentally get hit by the fan, on the
first day of job life,
he would come to give orientation of the refinery,
hello, hello, welcome chemical
engineers, today go to our refinery, welcome
to the Guru Gobind Singh Refinery, look at
our 2000 acre refinery, 2000 acres, such a
big refinery, it was fun to see it, what a thing, they
made it so big and it is not visible at all  He is saying that hey hey
what's the matter brother hey the
people who went to build it have not returned till date
I am fine brother it is a
big Relax refinery which is
extracting oil in one BHK
brother is saying do you know
which is the biggest refinery in India I said oh it is this
no it is Relax
I what is it on second I am on 10th
I am how many in total
12 I said you should learn to talk first
[Sangeet]
you have brought up this topic and friend I had dreams in college that when I get a
job I will wear formals, I will
wear a shirt I will fold the cuffs a little like this it looks
handsome like this what did we get to
wear there this this this you are
looking at this sister you will give leave to Hrithik Roshan in this
sister you do
n't wear this in this you enter in this
[Sangeet] it is
fire proof that is the only advantage so you
can extinguish the cigarette from it
[Prashansa]
and why should I say fire proof
because it keeps catching fire
it is not that once a fire broke out it keeps catching fire
present
continuous so on the first day itself he is
saying  Let me first teach you how to extinguish a fire.
I said, why are you saying fire extinguishing?
Look, his face is burning.
You have such a huge refinery of 2000 acres.
You don't have a fire department. You do have one, but it's
very far away. By the time they come, the fire has increased. They
come and say, "Now
everything is burnt," they throw water on us in anger and go away.
[Music]
I said, "Bring it closer." I had
brought that friend. Once there was a fire in the plant, that also got
burnt.
This is true, by Dave, it happened in the Panipat refinery
in the 90s. They had built such units
and in the middle they made a fire department, saying, "We will put it
here, we will put it out here. If it
explodes all at once, everyone is gone. No
one even noticed."
Then he said, "Come on, I will introduce you to your boss,
whose name is Sharad
Bhole, don't go there." He
took me to his office, it was a proper office. I
said, "Oh, what's the matter, I will come here, Sharad Sir, I am coming." He said, "
What happened?" I said, "Are you surprising
him?" I hid behind the sofa.
I came here as soon as I came.  I will go, the
new
joinee came, then Sharad
Bholu came and said hello welcome chemical
engineers welcome how did you like the
refinery a kid from here is saying sir
very
beautiful very
beautiful there was soot on his face he was
saying have you seen the refinery anybody has any
questions I said sir
how many holidays are there in this refinery
[music]
what I said holidays sir
leaves holidays for
Sunday brother
how many are available sir here arre 15 is
sick leave 15 is paid leave and 15 is casual
leave I
need
one tomorrow why do I need one I said question answer
why is it casual
brother be casual na you
this is what is casual leave take leave friend arre
what is your plan for a movie keeps watching movies
this is casual
behaviour he is getting serious on casual leave
so right Abhishek you can take a leave
tomorrow but I am just letting you know that we don't
I have no problem taking leaves, I don't need
encouragement, I am
very driven and motivated,
so it felt like relationships were turning sour on the very first day
[Sangeet]
Now, if a friend makes you stressed in the office,
you think whatever was to happen has happened,
okay, let's drink beer,
meet friends, vent out a bit, everything will be
fine, where should I go? There is
Talwandi Sabo, the
most happening place in that area, it
was the refinery, people would come to chill after the refinery, we will
talk in its light
[Sangeet] They had
given me a little township, I had to stay there,
I used to stay there, I am
calling my brother, I ask him what is he doing,
he is in Delhi, I said how are you, he said
what is he doing, he said
nothing brother, a new bar has opened in Gurgaon, we were going
there, we will go for a drink, there is also a live
gig, we will see that, then we will drink, then we will eat
brother, normal friend brother,
what are you doing, I am sitting,
friend  Go outside, I said it's forbidden to go out,
they were saying there are drug addicts roaming around and they
cut hands, they cut hands, they cut hands, they
cut my hands,
I got a boat here, you go out and your
hands get cut, if you go
inside your mouth gets burnt
[music]
So I started going down a little bit, I
saw a guy who looked like a local,
I said let's ask him, he might know
some hidden
gems, I called him, I said Paaji, what's
your name, he said
Gippy, I said Abhishek, he said
Pannu, he's
not even calling me Upmanyu, he does
n't even know, he's so lost in his heart, he's so deep in
Punjab,
I said Paaji, I wanted to ask if there are any
live gigs here, he said
Roin, I said no, Paaji, I want live ganja,
I don't want anything, Paaji, okay, let's meet,
I said wait, wait, if you have any important
work, tell me, I said like you need an abortion,
I said
what kind of place is this, Ganja and Bashan
markets are the same, the same
guy is selling both,
this is going on in Talwandi Saboo  And
smoking is not allowed inside the refinery.
They were saying that our
refinery will be ruined. It is a 2000 acre refinery. They get ruined by their speculation. So to
smoke there, I had to take a bus and go
half an hour away.
I used to sit in the bus and go half an hour away, smoke a
cigarette. Now it takes half an hour to come back. By the time we reach back, I
forget about smoking. Then
I went there for half an hour and
roamed around in buses for three days.
He gave a slip to the bus driver and said, "Friend,
you keep the bus, friend, I have learnt a little bit.
I have come to drive the bus
now." Obviously,
Sharad Bhole had a problem with this.
He called me to the office and called me to come here.
Your breaks have become very long. I said, "
Sir, I have to go out to smoke." Sir,
what should I do? Otherwise, why don't you smoke?
I said, "Sir, see, I will gradually
quit, I mean, how long are you taking alone? The
others are also working."
I said, "Sir, the others are smoking tobacco."
You also say Chani
Khani, what kind of job is this that you
want to start gutkha with your suit, I said no, then at least try Chani Khani,
I said friend, bring it, friend, and
I took that packet and kept it here,
I
enjoyed it, oh
[ __ ] friend, my Talwandi attitude started, I
found out, for two months I was not able to say it upstairs, then
I understood that it is
not going to work like this for long, so I said friend,
what should I do, I remembered, I have
45 leaves, I took them in the first 90 days itself, why delay
in doing a good work,
and all my leaves were also approved
because by chance, just by luck, the one who approved my leave was
an Englishman and you
know that Englishmen are sensitive people, they take every
disease seriously, I am calling, I can't come, I have a headache, oh
headache, I will pray
for
you, friend, please take some rest, I am opening a beer at home,
and tell this Indian Sharma Mishra Gupta,
sir, I have cancer, I will also come to the
office
[praise]
Come on, let's all work in cancer.
Here we recruit from cancer bud.
Come on,
friend, I spent the first three months having a lot of fun. I had a
big party in Chandigarh.
After three months, when I finally
reached the plant, Sharat Bhole was sitting
there and he was taunting me with marks.
I entered inside and said,
hey,
whose foot are you, Sadam Refinery is located,
good morning sir, what work do you have to do today,
you will work, sir, you give us work,
I will bring the cigarette, go,
hey, you
skipped the training, what work will
you do now, I said, then sir, should I go?
Card blasting will be done for unit one,
that too will not be done, I said, it will be done, so
he gave me the job of cardboard blasting.
What happens in it, basically, there is a
pipe going into the refinery,
so they start blowing air at one end of the pipe
and
stick a cardboard box at the opening of the pipe. Now if you
keep blowing air, the pressure will keep building,
after a point, so much pressure will build up that it will
blast and when it blasts, there is
a  A temporary vacuum is created
due to which all the dirt in the pipe gets
stuck to the cardboard. Now you
and I were equal chemical engineers.
Okay,
I have taught you everything you know. You can take the
exam in this room right now and you will get the same
marks.
[Music]
Correct.
51 Now friend, the thing is that when you do carbon
blasting like this, there is a blast sound. I
thought, friend, there is no feeling in one sound.
Why not set 10-12 pipes together and do it
like a Diwali party?
Then I set the pipes three to one. The
alarm started going off in the plant.
Immediately after this,
I said, "Save me, what is happening?"
Then I saw Sharad coming running in the bhole plant. He thinks
I have missed it. He
came there and said, "What is happening here?"
I said, "I am not tensed, we will do it
again.
Hey, sit down sir. Put the pipe in this way.
[Music]
Can I stop this right now? You have
created panic here." I said, "Sir, here,
Joy."  And the laughter is going on that let's go to
my office, you
took me to your office, whom should I ask,
you did blasting like this I said sir,
what difference does it make, sir, all the pipes are cleaned, does
n't it make a difference, with such a loud noise
any operator could have been scooped, an
accident could have happened, how would you know about
all this, you were not here during the training,
you took leave for 45 days out of 90, there were only
10 weekends,
six public holidays
and on the few days you have come, you keep
roaming in buses,
you do the training first, from tomorrow at
5:00 in the evening there is operator batch training,
sit in it, 5:00 to 9:00, I said sir, 5:00
to 9:00, so when will I come to the plant, will you
come at 9:00, whatever the time is, I said sir, then it will be
12 hours, you are saying you are busy sir,
somewhere I said sir, what will I do after
coming to the plant, when everything is prohibited, do the stance,
you will just do the stance, and you did low
level work  What do they do with that? They give
you a black marker, which
is a whiteboard. Take this, and on the
pipes that are going through, you just have to write by hand
which liquid or gas is going through them. I'm
writing here, map was ACIL, this is what I have to do. This is the
job they gave to a chemical
engineer. I would have done this in class 3,
my writing was better then, so
I'm doing this. Every day for eight hours,
12 hours.
HL A2 A4 Sharad Bhole is a fool.
I wrote that the neem leaves are bitter in the entire refinery.
[Music]
So this continued for two weeks. After two weeks,
one day I was writing like this, and the
alarm went off again in the plant. I said, I did
n't do anything, this time brother, I failed.
What did I write?
[Music] What
happened till then? There was an announcement in the plant. There has been a
naphtha leak
in unit one. Everyone is requested not to
move. The leak in unit one, please do not
move. It is a highly flammable gas that started
leaking. It is so flammable that if you move
here.  If it happens somewhere and I throw my shoe like this, there are
chances it will explode and it will
catch on something. So they said, don't
even move because that could cause an accident. So they
declared an emergency. I said, "[ __ ],
I might die here,
my life will end in Talwandi."
Now, the only way to stop that leakage was for
someone to go through it and close the
wall. But
whoever does this, his life is at major risk. He will
definitely die. So I said, "I'm
not doing it,
I don't have any interest in becoming a useless hero."
They told me to stand there.
I wasn't listening to them,
I was following them, thinking that
I would reach Chandigarh anyway.
[Music] Then
we saw Sharad Bhole going through that leakage.
I said, "Come
on, please, please, please, the
top two problems of my life can both
refinery and Sharad Bhole
go together." Please
go. God didn't listen to me, he came and
closed the wall.  There was a subsidence, they
shut down the plant for 12 hours and
told all the engineers to go to the office, the
plant will remain closed for 12 hours, everyone
reached when Sharad Bhole entered the plant office, the
entire refinery was clapping for him, saying that he is
getting such an applause break, the
refinery announced a bravery award for him,
10 lakh rupees was
not my annual salary, I was so
angry, okay, after that these
committees etc. sat, the inquiry committee said
we have done all the inquiries, someone had cancelled the guards
[music],
so Sharad ji called me to his office,
I reached the office, I said sir,
I am coming in, come in Abhishek, close the door, do
you know why I have called you here,
I said yes sir, technically I am entitled to a
share in that award,
shut up and you are talking
nonsense, you fool, people
could have lost their lives, are you
understanding, you are talking nonsense from above, you stupid
idiot, I
said sir please mind your language, I am deliberately
No, it has been
25 years since I have been in industry, I have
never seen an idiot like you. I
said, Sir, I did not do it intentionally,
and the operator should have been checked once. The
operator made a mistake.
Why do we keep people like you? They keep
coming, son. Be thankful that trainees cannot remove this person,
otherwise they would have kicked us out by kicking us in the ass. They keep coming for
25 years.
I said, Sir, please do your work,
I did not do it intentionally, and I
said sorry, what favor are you doing to me, you have come here by saying sorry, you have come here on the
recommendation of your father,
son, your father must also be a fool, why are you
staring like this, get out of here,
check one pipe and until all the pipes are fixed,
you should go, close the door and get out of here.
I felt that it was too much, so I
called my father, I said, Papa, these people are
abusing me,
son, a person learns from this too, be careful, friend,
you felt that this is too much, all this is beyond
my control, then I have
worked in all the companies of Delhi.  I
started applying to every company, I
sent messages saying, give me a job, give me a job, give me a
job, you give me a job, I
applied to a beauty parlor, I don't have the
passion for threading, please
give it to me,
friend, I used to do threading even with kite thread,
okay,
no one would reply, people would
reply to me like this, please stop bullying, this is how my
life has become, I used to go to the refinery every day, do
tensioning, come back and
sleep after spending 14 hours in this same dress, thank you, I did
not take it off for a month, I used to wear it,
I used to write and sleep like this, a month
passed like this, I started feeling depressed, almost
one day I was going back after writing like this,
inside the township, a voice came from behind, oh
Pannu oh
[music]
Pannu, what happened, why is your bangle torn,
I said friend, I stay in the office for a while, I will
meet you later,
okay, Gippy, what happened, tell me, I said, I will do it
later, friend, oh brother,
wait, what happened, I said, I am in a
bad mood,  If you are in a bad mood, let's fix it,
how am I saying? I am crying. I said I do
n't want to do heroine, friend, why shouldn't
I do it, because she is a heroine, that's enough
reason, he's saying not to do it. Okay, the
whole of Punjab is crazy about it.
I'm not saying that the whole of Punjab is doing it. Some
people do it, okay, the drug addict is saying it, that's what
I'm saying. Pannu, you don't have to become a drug addict, friend, you have to do it sometimes. I'm saying, you do it all day, do it in balance, you don't have to do too much, friend, if you eat too much, it's also harmful. I said, you're right, friend, I'm
saying, we are employed
people, we don't have time to do
drugs every day. I've never done it, the root is
bad. I've done it, I haven't done it, it's the same.
I said, okay, I'm saying, listen, don't like it, don't do it, I'm not going to give you an injection. I said, okay, come
with me. It's 10:00 now,
I'll drop you back here by 1 o'clock. I
said, okay, come with me.  I took him to a
place which was a forest, there was a hospital there which was
closed, three-four boys were sitting there and
sleeping, I couldn't see it, okay, really they were
half asleep, I said
you
guys go to sleep, I took him, he took a piece, put it on the spoon,
applied a lighter from below, drew out the liquid,
injected it, I said this is the first shot brother, I am saying, you will do it
yourself, I said myself, I was just about to do it, when
I got a call,
I said hello Abhishek, is it Abhishek, I
said yes Abhishek, I am Aditi calling from
Integral office, is this a good time to
talk, yes yes very
good
time, so where did  Do you apply for a position
of junior analyst in a company I said yes I did I am done I am coming right now I can join right now I can join right now can I come
please can't no Abhishek so tomorrow is the
interview round and written an interview your
resume has been shortlisted for that would you be able
to make it I said yes I can
come right now can it
start at 9:00 tomorrow
I said ok I am coming just one
last thing Abhishek so your current package is 6
lakhs per annum how ever we offer only 3 lakhs per annum
to our junior analyst would that be all right
I said can you give me ₹ per day I
just need that much ok I am coming right now
I will sit outside the office ok bye
ma'am thank you see you man see you I
said oh Gippy I am going there is some important work to do
abortion I said no friend there are more
important things
in the world I immediately boarded a bus and went to Bathinda  I
went to Delhi and gave the interview there and
I told a lot of lies in the interview, I should
n't tell so many lies,
I really feel till today that something bad will happen in life, right? That's why I told so many lies
in that interview
Abhishek and my biggest weakness is that I ca
n't sleep without work,
wow Abhishek,
wow, I get hired by telling these lies,
after two-three months the company comes to know
what a fool he has made of
us, he
drank coffee after getting this offer,
sugar packets are coming out of our pocket,
what is this, I
gave all these interviews, I was
standing outside the office with the interviewer, the HR lady came out,
she said hi Abhishek, this is this company, I decided
to make you an offer, congratulations, I sent
you all the details of the email, I said thank
you, I immediately called Chuchu, I said
brother, I got the job, I am coming to Delhi, he said oh
what's the matter, tell me brother, in this happiness I will
drink alcohol and vomit, I got a
doctor, only one work was left,
I went back to Bathinda, resigned,
one month's notice was paid, I served the full notice, did not
say anything, last jiddi,
I was going to go to Delhi, Sharad  I went to Bholo's office and said
Sir I am leaving okay go I had something to
tell you say yes sir not a day goes by when
I don't wish
that you would have died in the leakage that day what
nonsense are you talking I said do
n't interrupt when I am speaking okay that's the
marker you gave me to write with I will
write Chucha on your forehead and it will
also improve your face what are you
showing off show your status I said I am showing your
status do whatever you want bhaiya and go and
check each and every sense I have written your horoscope on
each one I am
leaving spit on you cheap office brought spit
in a box to throw it while leaving where there was
Chucha security and
paper weight I dropped that too moved away
went out I had a lot of fun till
today I am proud of that
forget about Bathinda and Talwandi and all this
life is bad I went to Lilli where
I joined the company I started enjoying it on the first day itself
hearing the voice of their HR like that  Hey
mujhe aise nahay dhoe formal a smile
first day atcher hello Abhishek my name is Adi hello hello
Abhishek just let you know today will be a
light day I love light
day my favourite
day is my story now the office start showing me the office
Abhishek this is a game room you know there a
football table the pool table I said game
room ok ok just done I think so this
balcony is the smoking area I said right here
you can literally inhale and exhale smoke outside I
mean oh very correct this is so do you have
any question about the company
I said what's your leave system
like Abhishek we don't have a leave system
we trust our apple so never you want to take a leave just take a leave
[Music]
I started crying there
I said aapko main salary denge yaar bach company hai
club hai koi ya I will take it he made me sit
Abhishek we have everything now all we need is
a reference letter
from a previous
[Music]
Boss, that's why I'm doing comedy.
Thank you for coming, guy. I hope you had a
good
time. Thank you for coming. You're taking the photo. Take it,
man. No problem, the issue is over now.
Thanks for coming. Hope this was worth
your time and money. Thanks a lot. Have a
good night, bye bye.
[Music]